Ali AGHABABAEI

 ♦ Room 324, Laboratoire d'Informatique de Grenoble, University of Grenoble Alpes
 ☑ Email

L +33 638 233343

𝚱 aah94.github.io

in Linkdein

♦ Scholar

Summary

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at the Université Grenoble Alpes, supervised by Professor Massih-Reza Amini. I am actively exploring a diverse range of topics within machine learning and deep learning, aiming to advance scalable AI solutions through improved model efficiency.

Education

Université Grenoble Alpes

2023 - Present

Ph.D. in Computer Science

 $\circ\,$ Research: Efficient Machine Learning

Sharif University of Technology

2018 - 2022

M.Sc. in Computer Science 🗹

o Coursework: Deep Learning, Speech Processing

University of Tehran

2013 - 2018

B.Sc. in Electrical Engineering

o Coursework: Linear Algebra, Pattern Recognition, Digital Signal Processing

Research Interests

Generative AI

Efficient Deep Learning

o Tensor Decomposition

• Diffusion Generative AI

• Knowledge Distillation

 \circ Image Reconstruction

Model Pruning

• Image Manipulate

Inverse Problems

- Image Denoising
- Image Super Resolution
- MRI and CT Imaging

Research Experience

Ph.D. Thesis

2023 - Present

APTIKAL team 🗹

- Developed an innovative approach to reduce computational complexity and parameters of deep learning models using tensor decomposition techniques.
- Designed a constraint-based loss function to identify optimal tensor decomposition ranks for pre-trained models, enhancing model efficiency while preserving accuracy.
- Investigated the effectiveness of the proposed method in optimizing Vision Transformer (ViT) models for improved efficiency and performance.

Research Collaborator

2021 - 2022

University of Basel

- Conducted analysis of inverse problems, including image denoising, limited-view computed tomography (CT), and wave scattering, utilizing invertible neural networks.
- Approximate data distribution with normalizing flow to identify out-of-distribution samples, improving model robustness and reliability.

M.Sc. Thesis

Electronic Research Institute

• Proposed a patch-wise feature analysis approach for identifying forgery in video frames, aimed at enhancing deepfake detection capabilities.

 Developed a straightforward method to enhance the generalization and robustness of deepfake detection models.

B.Sc. Thesis

University of Tehran

• Designed and implemented a video quality meter to assess video quality in terms of blockiness and blurriness distortions in a no-reference mode.

Publications

Unified Framework for Neural Network Compression via Decomposition and Optimal Rank Selection

Oct 2024

Ali Aghababaei-Harandi, Massih-Reza Amini

arxiv.org/pdf/2409.03555 **☑**

Deep variational inverse scattering

Mar 2023

Amir
Ehsan Khorashadizadeh, $\boldsymbol{Ali~Aghababaei\text{-}Harandi},$ Tin Vlašić, Hieu Nguyen,

Ivan Dokmanić

European Conference on Antennas and Propagation

Conditional injective flows for Bayesian imaging

Feb 2023

Amir
Ehsan Khorashadizadeh, Konik Kothari, Leonardo Salsi,
 $\boldsymbol{Ali~Aghabaei\text{-}Harandi},$

Maarten de Hoop, Ivan Dokmanić

IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging

Skills

Programming Tools: Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Java

Theoretical: Pattern Recognition, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Creative Problem Solving